

EMILY CLARK

Art Director & UI/UX Designer

CONTACT

WEBSITE

emilyclark.design

EMAIL

emilyblaineclark@gmail.com

CONNECT



emilyblaineclark

CAPABILITIES

SKILLS

Art Direction

UI/UX Design

Digital

Print

Visual Branding

Logo Systems

Social Media

TOOLS

Sketch App InVision App

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

PROFILE

My career as a designer has spanned more than a decade. I've worked on a variety of projects for a broad range of clients. Over that time, I've earned a reputation as a driven, forward-looking, and goal-oriented designer. That's why at work I join my creative energy with effective collaboration, efficient processes, and clear communication.

EXPERIENCE

AUGUST 2014 - PRESENT ART DIRECTOR | DBS INTERACTIVE

I play a senior role in every design asset the agency produces. As Art Director, I work with developers, marketers, copy writers, account executives, and clients themselves to ensure every design meets the high standards we set.

- Designed wireframes and mockups for more than 55 digital products including websites, apps, and infographics
- Worked with a team of 6-10 in-house and contract designers and developers on website projects
- Led hour-long design discovery sessions during in-person client meetings
- Worked as lead designer on a variety of special projects, including interactive infographics, apps, software GUIs, and social media campaigns
- Created variety of offline marketing assets, including product catalogs, trade show booths, brochures, and magazine ads
- Launched new businesses as the design lead on a team of branding specialists, digital marketers, and developers

JULY 2010 – AUGUST 2014 SENIOR DESIGNER | THE VICKSBURG POST

I grew from an entry level position to leading the newspaper's design team. As Senior Designer, I was responsible for collaborating with the managing editor, photographers, and the sales team to execute the daily design for the paper.

- Planned and designed layout of daily paper on a strict deadline and under tight pressure
- Designed a multitude of special-edition magazines
- Photographed a variety of events and stories
- · Authored occasional articles while on assignment



EMILY CLARK

Art Director & UI/UX Designer

CONTACT

WEBSITE

emilyclark.design

EMAIL

emilyblaineclark@gmail.com

CONNECT

in 💿

emilyblaineclark

10 yrs

PROFESSIONAL DESIGN EXPERIENCE

3 yrs

DIGITAL & UI/UX
DESIGN EXPERIENCE

AGENCY EXPERIENCE

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

MAY 2008 – JULY 2010 FREELANCE DESIGNER & ARTIST | SELF-EMPLOYED

As a freelancer, I worked with a number of local businesses to design marketing assets that promoted their brand within the community.

JUNE 2007 – JUNE 2008
SENIOR DESIGNER | THE SOUTH MAGAZINE

At *The South*, I worked as an assistant art director, designing spreads for feature articles, and managing contract photographers and stylists at shoots.

EDUCATION

2003 - 2007 SAVANNAH COLLEGE OF ART AND DESIGN

SCAD

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Graphic Design, Cum Laude

- Art Directors Club National Portfolio Review, New York, New York, 2006 2007
- · Minor in Photography
- National Dean's List, nominated by Professor Fathi Bakkoush, 2006 2007
- Dean's List, Savannah, Georgia, Fall 2003 Winter 2006

AWARDS

2016 HORIZON INTERACTIVE AWARDS

- Mighty Small Homes, Website, Best In Category (Real Estate), as Lead Designer and Art Director of DBS Interactive
- Make Your Dollar SOAR!, Interactive Infographic, Leadership Louisville Center, Gold (Promotional), as Lead Designer and Art Director of DBS Interactive
- Build Your Snowman, Website, DBS Interactive, Silver (Self Promotion/Portfolio), aas Lead
 Designer and Art Director of DBS Interactive

2016 SUMMIT EMERGING MEDIA AWARD

• Make Your Dollar SOAR!, Interactive Infographic, Leadership Louisville Center, Silver Innovator Award (Event Marketing), as Lead Designer and Art Director of DBS Interactive